Come on!
Drink up.
Pinako...
Mind if I join you?
Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
Interlude Party
It's nice to let loose like this every once in a while.
You probably think we're the most carefree people on earth, don't you?
But who can blame us?
This country's always at war.
And now there's something going on over in Ishval... is that all this country is good for?
They never learn.
Humans are foolish, pitiful creatures.
With Ishbal and other riots...
the East sure have their hands full.
Not just the East, but there are riots and border wars
sparking up in the North and the West.
Skirmishes are still ongoing on the border with Aerugo to the south and Creta to the west.
And there's still the great nation of Drachma up north, too.
Mountains of corpses everywhere, huh...
We may even get a coup soon...
Such a scary country to be in...
This country's been so military-focused ever since King Bradley became the Führer President.
Hey, let's dance!
You're quite the stud, Hohenheim!
Why don't you go dance by yourself?
But that's no fun!
This man isn't fancy enough to dance.
Come on, go dance with those girls over there.
I think that's about how old they were...
...when they started to even think about something like human transmutation.
Why didn't you take a stand as
their father and say something to them?
Even if I did, it wouldn't change the fact they'd have to repent for their sins.
You're harsh.
A sin is a sin.
Dammit!!!
They took it away!!!
Help me... someone...
Mom... Mom...
No way... No...
This isn't...
This isn't what I wanted!!!
Al... Alphonse...
Alphonse! Alphonse!
Because of me...
Alphonse!!!
Dammit... Dammit!!!
Give him back... He's my little brother...
Whether it be an arm or a leg...
Or even my heart! You can take it!
So give him back...
He's my only brother!!!
A heavenly stone that destroyed Xerxes overnight.
If we had this, we could get your body back...
Doctor, what exactly were you ordered to research?
The Philosopher's Stone.
You mustn't desire such a thing.
That is the Devil's research.
You'll see Hell if you study it.
"The Devil's research"...
"Something you mustn't desire"...
I resent you, Dr. Marcoh...
The ingredients of philosopher's stones...
...are live humans.
Fragile beings, don't you think?
They cower at the darkness and don't try to stand up to it.
And instead, they try to forget it temporarily and try to escape from reality.
Humans are such weak creatures.
Well, let's have them be of some use
to us as a precious resource.
Eh, Hohenheim?
"You may be able to reach
the real truth that is beyond truth"...
What the heck is this?
Could it be what's used to transmute philosopher's stones?
Let's see how good you are.
Looks like that arm saved your life!
But my beloved sword even slices through steel!
Brother!
It's shameful, but we lost.
You're not going to say something like, "Hey, we're actually a trio", are ya?
We won't, we won't.
Just destroy us already, boy.
Spare me from having to murder someone.
You consider us human?
If I didn't accept you two as human,
it would mean I'm doing the same to my brother, too.
My little brother is human.
And so are you two.
That's why I don't want to kill you.
Brother?
Us two have been stealing, destroying,
and murdering ever since we came of age.
And we're being treated as humans for the first time, after being turned into this?
Interesting.
I'll tell you everything as a parting gift, boy.
The one who created the philosopher's stone and told us to guard this place is...
That was close.
You can't be saying out things like that, 48.
You're so annoying, dumbass!
You guys were about to kill a precious sacrifice!
Don't you understand?!
Who the hell are you two?!
What plan?!
What do you mean by sacrifice?!
You're a human sacrifice, right?
Y-Yeah, that's right. I'm a human sacrifice!
What the heck does he mean by that?
...and perhaps their master, too... may also be a suitable sacrifice
I'm sorry.
You're a candidate for sacrifice,
but you're going to die here.
I've been thinking for some time..
...as to what you mean by "human sacrifice"...
...and about what you are trying to make me do..
Riots throughout Lior.
The ingredients of philosopher's stone are humans...
What we did in Ishval...
Whoa now, who's the mastermind behind all of this?
What you are trying to do right now...
...is to create a giant transmutation circle, using this country and its people.
And the purpose of that...
...is to create a philosopher's stone. Am I right?
Could it be that you actually knew?
Hohenheim.
Why didn't you tell anyone?
Hohenheim!
Even if I had, would that have changed anything?
What?
I've been watching them for some time.
The humans who continue to repeat the same mistakes without end.
And the same humans who had to helplessly escape from their actions.
Humans are fragile creatures.
I thought I told you.
The philosopher's stone is my core.
I'm a homunculus.
You've heard of them, have you?
Humans that were created artificially.
That's what I am.
We're all going to die here anyway.
I'll show you something cool as a final gift.
Can I eat him?
Mustang!!!
The monster was keeping another monster inside its belly!
It swallowed everything around him!
So even something like this is created...
...by alchemy...
Who are you, old man?
Just as you have an ultimate shield,
I have an ultimate eye.
Oh, now I get it, Hughes...
When you said that the army was in danger...
...you didn't mean a crisis was approaching the army...
You meant that the army itself was in a crisis.
Father? You have a dad?
I do.
The one who created the Homunculi?
Yes.
Humans don't have an ultimate spear or an ultimate shield.
Nevertheless, the most trivial things get the best of them, making them unable to get back up.
What can creatures like that do against homunculi?
Even so, we won't give up!
We wouldn't give up for the world!
That's also a human trait, isn't it?
How can you even move with that wound?!
I sealed it with fire!
Although I almost fainted a few times.
No matter how many times you try, you can't win.
How about you tell me the secret now?
Thanks for that.
The blood that was all up in my head went away, and I can think clearly now.
You're still going to resist?
Let this put you to sleep!
This body comes with many inconveniences.
But inconveniences don't make me miserable!
There's no reason for you to pity me!
My life was put together with alchemy by my brother.
If I deny myself, that would mean that I'm denying brother, along with alchemy.
I believe in the potential that alchemy holds.
I want to believe in it!
A State Alchemist!
Get down!
Hang in there...
Don't die!
D-Dammit... It won't stop bleeding...
Someone...
Live...
You can't die.
Lan Fan!
Run!
Lan Fan!!!
My left arm is...
What's wrong?!
Young Master!
I can no longer be of any use to you!
Lan Fan?!
Don't do it!
Well played.
No matter how many times we're stepped on...
No matter how many times we fall...
We'll get back up and keep walking.
And someday...
That's just a useless struggle.
You don't know until you try!
It's better than not doing anything at all!
Are you fine with that?!
If Ed, Al, and everyone else disappears?!
Why are you getting so worked up?
Even if we do work for the sake of the humans,
they'll just end up dying in the end.
It all becomes wasted effort on our side.
In that case, don't you think it's wiser to simply grab what's important and run away?
What did y-
A bit of your conscience?
Or a worthless sentiment?
Eh, Hohenheim?
No matter how hard you try,
no one will accept you anymore!
Just look at your own face!
Humans are nothing but a resource to be used.
And if you leave them be, they'll renew themselves.
Why would you need to do anything?
Would that change anything?
Would you be able to change reality?!
Would you be able to change how these weak humans are?!
We can change.
We'll be able to change.
I'm sure of it.
We really are weak creatures,
but that's why we can strive to become stronger.
Even if you feel it's useless,
each step we take leads to something great.
A subordinate protects their subordinate, and so forth.
That should be possible, even for us puny humans.
No... I wasn't prepared enough.
Lan Fan was more prepared than I was.
Seeing people die before my eyes...
I hate it! I'm tired of it!
I'm not going to let anyone die anymore! I'll protect you!
No way in hell am I going to run!
After I beat the shit out of that "truth" guy, I'm going to drag your body out of there!
Al!
Al! Come here!
Hurry up! Al!!!
Alphonse!
Wait for me.
That's why I'm sure we'll be able to change.
Because we're weak... and because death is inevitable...
Humans try their best to live and end up becoming stronger.
If your heart is still hesitating...
Try to remember.
The days you spent in Resembool with us.
A dream, huh...
Thanks for everything.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
If you'll cower at the sight of the great foe before you,
leave at once, coward.
If you'll lose the strength you believed in,
then fall to the ground, weakling.
Now is the time for the decisive battle.
Humans, give it all you have.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Father
Episode 28, Father.